ur-browser.com 2019-04-16

# Privacy policy - UR Browser

#### ADAPTIVEBEE S.A.S.U.

## PRIVACY POLICY

#### Last modified: 05-Apr-2019

“privacy by design” - UR’s credo - and “we”, ADAPTIVEBEE are committed to building it and thus to the protection of our end user privacy, and therefore focus and make best efforts to handle and store data only in the European Union, as well as limiting most information reaching third-parties.

###  1\. What is the Privacy Policy and its implications 

The ADAPTIVEBEE Privacy Policy describes how we treat various types of information when you use ADAPTIVEBEE 's products and services, including when you use UR Browser to access those products and services. This ADAPTIVEBEE Privacy Notice describes the privacy practices that are specific to UR Browser.

We, at AdavptiveBee SASU (“Company” or “we”, “us”) take our users privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs the manner in which we collect, use, maintain and disclose information collected from users (each, a “user” or “you”) while they use our browser, known as “UR” developed and owned solely by us ("Browser" or “UR Browser” or “UR”) including the various features implemented therein (collectively, the “Service(s)”).

This Privacy Policy is an integrated part of the Company’s End User License Agreement (available at: [https://www.ur-browser.com/eula](https://www.ur-browser.com/eula) ) (“Terms”) and is legally binding agreement between you and the Company. The Privacy Policy and Terms shall be binding upon any use or attempt to use our Services including the download and install of the UR Browser. Definitions herein shall have the same meaning as defined in the EULA.

By using the UR Browser or our Services you hereby agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy. Any use or continued use of the Browser constitutes your agreement and consent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access, download, install or use the UR Browser or Services in any manner. 

We reserve the right to periodically amend or revise the Privacy Policy at our sole discretion. Such changes and updates will be effective immediately upon the display of the revised Privacy Policy. Thus, we encourage you to check this Privacy Policy regularly for updates, so that you are fully informed of how your data is collected and used by the Company and your related rights. The last revision date will be reflected in the "Last Modified" heading. Your continued use of the Service following the display of such amendments constitutes your acknowledgement and consent to such amendments to the Privacy Policy and your agreement to be bound by the terms of such amended policy. In the event of material changes that will adversely affect your use of the Service or the data collection by us, we will make best efforts to provide you with notification through the Browser or Services.

###  2.How does ADAPTIVEBEE treat information while using UR

**A)** Information that identifies you as an individual or may with reasonable effort be used to identify you as an individual ("Personal Information"), can be stored **ONLY IF** voluntarily provided by you in the following events: 

  * (i) Personal Information voluntarily provided by you if and when you contact us, which may include your name and email address, provided that such information will be used solely to communicate with and support you, and will not be shared with any third parties;
  * (ii) Personal Information voluntarily provided by you if and when you choose to become a registered user of the Service;

You do not need to provide any personally identifying information in order to use UR browser to a limited extent, and we do not collect such information.

**B)** Another type of information is browsing data that is stored locally on your device like browsing history information, cookies, add-ons data, download index and other files used in navigation. This data in aggregated Non-Personal Information in most cases, however, sometimes browsing history or the search history contains terms that might identify you. 

We will treat the browsing data as Personal Information. We will not collect any data regarding to this aspect.

At any time, you can choose to delete your browsing history information, in whole or in part. To protect your privacy and provide you with secure browsing experience you can choose to have UR Browser save your passwords for specific websites. Stored passwords can be reviewed in UR Browser settings and will be treated as sensitive and Personal Information with high security standard. You can configure UR Browser through it features to always not accept cookies, block trackers, advertisements from ADAPTIVEBEE or any other sites, or just in certain cases by using private browsing, Ninja Mode, or via specific privacy features provided by UR Browser.

In NinjaMode, private browsing, UR Browser will not store basic browsing history information such as URLs, cached page text, or IP addresses of pages linked from the websites you visit. It will also not store snapshots of pages that you visit or keep a record of your downloads (although this information could still be stored elsewhere on your system, e.g. in a list of recently opened files).

Learn more about configuring cookies and site data in UR and privacy settings via our [FAQ.](https://www.ur-browser.com/en-US/Faq)

**C)** When you use UR, the only type of information we may collect is non-identifiable aggregated information which is made available via the user use of the Browser ("Non-Personal Information"). We are not aware of the identity of the user from whom the Non-Personal Information is collected. By default, ADAPTIVEBEE receives standard anonymous diagnostic usage data, please refer to Terms for additional info. This information is only used to improve the user experience, to fix and improve the software, retain locally your custom browser services settings. 

If you use UR Browser to access other ADAPTIVEBEE services the fact that you are using UR Browser does not cause ADAPTIVEBEE to receive any special or additional personally identifying information about you.

UR Browser periodically contacts ADAPTIVEBEE to perform functions such as checking for updates, checking connectivity status, validating current time, and estimating the number of active users. Each copy of UR Browser includes a temporary randomly-generated installation number which will be sent to ADAPTIVEBEE when you install and first use the product. The temporary number will be promptly deleted the first time that UR Browser automatically checks for updates. If you received or reactivated your copy of the UR Browser as part of a promotional campaign, it may generate a unique token which is sent to ADAPTIVEBEE when you first run and use the browser after installation, reinstallation, or reactivation. Furthermore, field trials may result in different variations of UR Browser, and UR Browser may send non-unique information to ADAPTIVEBEE about which variation is active;

UR may send technical usage statistics and crash reports to ADAPTIVEBEE. This setting will apply to all users for a given installation of UR Browser. The usage statistics and crash reports help us diagnose problems, help us understand how users interact with UR Browser, and help us improve UR Browser's performance;

UR does not send information that identifies you personally. Crash reports, however, can contain anonymous system information at the time of a malfunction, and errors leading up to a malfunction.

We value your privacy and control over your Non-Personal Identifiable Information, and therefore you may, at any time, request to have your Non-Personal Identifiable Information collected from you deleted from our servers. To exercise that right, please contacting us at: contact [at] adaptivebee.com. In the event you make such a request, note that we may require certain information from you in order to verify your identity and locate your data and that the process of locating and deleting the data may take reasonable time and effort. Data privacy and related laws in your jurisdiction may provide you with different or additional rights related to the data we collect from you, which may also apply.

Unless you decide to delete your account or any part thereof, or instruct us otherwise, we retain the information we collect for as long as needed to provide the Service and to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements, alongside we are making best efforts to be compliant with European Commission’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), for more info visit [www.eugdpr.org](http://www.eugdpr.org/)

**D)** The Weather widget of the UR Homescreen feature uses your location to automatically display relevant information. The widget communicates with a third-party server, this in order to provide you with such valid weather information. No personally identifiable, unrelated to location, information is collected, stored or shared via this feature with third parties. ADAPTIVEBEE does receive standard anonymous usage data, only for internal statistical purposes and in accordance to this Privacy Policy;

When we do need to collect the above mentioned limited, anonymous, aggregated data, **we do not disclose nor sell it** for commercial or other uses, we use it to improve UR.

**E)** The VPN feature uses your location just to show you what your current location is from web services perspective. More exactly, to show you what is the location that other websites and web-applications will detect when you will access them. ADAPTIVEBEE does receive standard anonymous feature-related usage data, only for internal statistical and improvement purposes, in accordance to this Privacy Policy; The third parties offering VPN services to UR browser, have been carefully selected and are either fully operating under EU jurisdiction or abiding EU privacy laws; They agreed not to collect, log, disclose nor sell data, moreover they don’t have access to your UR account. Read more in section 7. Service Providers 

###  3\. What information do website operators receive when you visit a site using UR 

Sites that you visit using UR Browser will automatically receive standard log information similar to that received by ADAPTIVEBEE. These sites may also set their own cookies or store site data on your system. You can restrict cookies and other site data in UR Browser's preferences page.

If you use UR Browser in private browsing or having PrivacySuite set on medium/high it will not transmit any pre-existing cookies to sites that you visit. Sites may deposit new cookies on your system while you are in these modes; these cookies will only be temporarily stored and transmitted to sites while you remain in incognito / PrivacySuite medium/high. They will be deleted when you close the browser, close all open incognito windows or exit.

If you choose to use UR Browser’s location feature, this service allows you to share your location with a site. UR Browser will not allow a site to access your location without your permission. ADAPTIVEBEE does not have control over third party websites or their privacy practices.

Please carefully consider any website’s privacy practices before consenting to share your location with that website.

###  4\. Using apps, extensions, themes, services, and other add-ons with UR Browser

You may use apps, extensions, themes, services and other add-ons ("Add-ons") with UR browser, including some that may be pre-installed or integrated with UR Browser and some that you may obtain from other sources.

Before installing an Add-on, you should review the requested permissions. Add-ons may be designed to store, access, and share data stored locally or in your online accounts. Add-ons may use notifications that are sent through ADAPTIVEBEE servers. UR Browser may check for, download, and install updates to your Add-ons. UR Browser may send usage indicators to ADAPTIVEBEE for installed Add-ons. Some add-ons might require access to a unique identifier for digital rights management or for delivery of push messaging. You can disable the use of such an identifier by removing the add-on from UR Browser.

Add-ons developed and provided by ADAPTIVEBEE may communicate with ADAPTIVEBEE servers and are subject to these Policies unless otherwise indicated. Add-ons developed and provided by third parties are the responsibility of such third parties and may be subject to third party privacy policies. For example, a version of the Adobe Flash Player plug-in is preinstalled, but disabled, with UR Browser. 

Information that other website, services, add-ons operators receive is subject to the privacy policies of those websites. 

###  5\. What is Opt-Out Right

Even after providing your consent to this Privacy Policy, you are entitled to change your mind. If you do, you may opt out of the data collection and sharing process related to our Services, by adjusting the “Settings” menu in the Browser. After you opt out, we will no longer collect and share your data as described in this Privacy Policy in connection with your use of the Browser or Services. Note that once you opt out, part of the Services provided by us might no longer be available.

###  6\. What is Phishing

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to ADAPTIVEBEE. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your username, password or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the [European Commission’s Press Release](http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-17-631_en.htm) website.

###  7\. Service providers 

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related actions (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Site or Application’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site and Application are used. These third parties don’t have access to your Non-Personal Identifiable Information and are obligated not to disclose or use any user information for any other purpose. Moreover, and on top of the above, we make necessary efforts to mask, proxy through our servers any end-user data that needs to be transferred to a third-party, in order to completely decorrelate data and end-users.

OpenWeatherMap enables UR browser to check and display weather forecasts in real time when using UR Homescreen, we may share Non-Personal Information, for more information about the way your information will be collected, please read please read [OpenWeatherMap’s Privacy Policy ](https://openweathermap.org/privacy-policy)

We’ve carefully chosen OVPN to power UR VPN service, because of their excellent reputation, having a true [ NO LOGS policy ](https://www.ovpn.com/en/blog/logs-not-at-ovpn/) and being based in Europe as well. Please read more about [ OVPN’s Privacy Policy ](https://www.ovpn.com/en/privacypolicy), and acknowledge that by using UR VPN you agree also with their [ Privacy Policy ](https://www.ovpn.com/en/privacypolicy). 

[ Stripe ](https://stripe.com/) is our online payments solutions provider and **no payment information is stored with us.**

Ads appearing on our Services may be delivered to users by our advertising partners, who may use cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile Non-Personal Information about you. This Privacy Policy does not cover or govern the use of cookies by any applicable advertisers. Although using PrivacySuite in a Medium or High state will block all third-party cookies including these ones, for more information please review the [FAQ.](https://www.ur-browser.com/en-US/Faq)

You will be presented with and have access to links to other websites through your use of our Site(s) and the Application. If you choose to visit an advertiser by “clicking on” a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third-party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website. The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

###  8\. Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

ADAPTIVEBEE cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of ADAPTIVEBEE or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

###  9\. Business Transfers

ADAPTIVEBEE may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy, making best efforts in maintaining a privacy and security philosophy of the products and services offered.

###  10\. Security

ADAPTIVEBEE is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored “personal data” (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via conspicuous posting on this Site in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

###  11\. International Transfer

Your information will be transferred to the European Union and maintained on European Union’s computers. If this is located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the European Union and choose to provide information to us, ADAPTIVEBEE transfers this information to the European Union and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

###  12\. How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at contact [at] adaptivebee.com.

### ADAPTIVEBEE

  * Attention: Privacy Issues 
  * 20, rue Bouvier, 75011 Paris 
  * Address: [contact [at] adaptivebee.com](mailto:contact@adaptivebee.com)
  * Website: [http://www.adaptivebee.com](http://www.adaptivebee.com/)
